

# Joseph David

# **Mechanical Engineer**

Experienced professional in Project Management/Planning, Air-conditioning and Mechanical Ventilation, Project Coordination/Supervision, Quantity Surveying, Drafting, Design and Maintenance of MEPS and willing to learn and improve my knowledge as a mechanical engineer for the benefit of the Company.

29jojodavid@gmail.com

0915-593-8046



Angeles City, Philippines

in linkedin.com/in/JosephLdavid

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

# **Project Engineer** HPH TECHNOLOGIES PTE LTD

06/2018 - 06/2020

SINGAPORE

HPH Technologies focuses on manufacturing, integration and installation of security communication and electrical control systems.

#### Tasks/Responsibilities

- Studies project specification and project plan based on customer requirements
- Coordinating with cross-discipline team members to make sure that all parties are on track with project requirements, deadlines, and schedules.
- Meeting with project team members to identify and resolve issues.
- Submitting project deliverables and ensuring that they adhere to quality standards.
- Preparing status reports by gathering, analyzing, and summarizing relevant information.
- Establishing effective project communication plans and ensuring their execution.
- Facilitating change requests to ensure that all parties are informed of the impacts on schedule and budget.
- · Coordinating the development of user manuals, training materials, and other documents as needed to enable successful implementation and turnover of the process or system to the clients.

#### **Cadet Engineer**

# Sentine Industrial and Building Solutions

01/2016 - 02/2018

**Philippines** 

#### Tasks/Responsibilities

- Performs Quantity Surveys and Cost Estimates for costumers involving the General requirement of the project, Labor cost & material cost for each
- Surveying on site construction & development for actual computation of heat loads, capacities of air-condition units, required air exchange for exhaust systems.
- Designing of AC systems (Single split system & VRF system of Aircondition) for mechanical plan of a project Commercial Buildings.
- · Coordinates with the Design Consultants when clarifications, drawings and other related documents.
- Ensures adequate safety precautions are enforced on site.

# **EDUCATION**

**Bachelor of Science in Mechanical Engineering** Holy Angel University

06/2009 - 03/2015

Secondary Systems Plus College Foundation

# **SKILLS**

MS Office Self Motivated

# **CERTIFICATES**

PRC Mechanical Engineer license (10/2015 - Present)

License no. 0089680

REVIT MEP Training (02/2018 - 03/2018)

Certificate No. 18126234321

Technical Forum on Psychrometric Analysis (06/2016)

HVAC-R Air-conditioning Design for Energy Savings (10/2017)

**HVAC-R Case Studies for High Efficiency** Chiller Systems (10/2017)

ISO 45001 Management System/OHSMS (10/2017)

# **ORGANIZATIONS**

Philippines Society Of Mechanical Engineers (10/2015)

#### **LANGUAGES**

Filipino



English



